Mariko! Good morning!
真理子 早安
Good morning. Morning, Shuji.
早安
When I got home yesterday…
我昨天回家的时候…
She's turned out pretty cute after she got her hair cut.
她剪头发之后 变得很可爱
But why is there an aura of depression just around Nobuta?
但为什么野猪身边 总有一股阴郁的氛围？
There's something she's lacking.
她究竟缺少了什么？
DEAR NOBUKO KOTANI
（亲爱的小谷信子）
"I love…"
“我…
"I love you"?
喜欢你？”
What is it that Nobuta's lacking?
野猪缺少的是什么？
-That's right. -Oh, don't say that!
-没错 -不许你这么说
Oh, that's what it is!
原来是这样啊
That's it!
就是这个
What Nobuta lacks is that flirty way of talking around guys!
野猪缺少的 就是跟男生撒娇的说话方式
It sure doesn't sound like you're joking!
一点都不像在开玩笑
That trick of twisting coyly so she looks cute to guys!
娇羞地扭动身体 这一招会让男生觉得很可爱
I'll never forgive you.
人家永远都不原谅你啦
That's it!
就是这个
The skills for attracting guys.
吸引男人的技巧
That's what it is.
原来是这样
What Nobuta lacks is communication with guys!
野猪缺少的就是跟男生的交流
In other words, the experience of love.
换句话说 就是恋爱经验
Love…
恋爱啊…
-Love?
-恋爱啊 -恋爱呀
What? You still haven't left for school?
什么？你还没去学校吗？
Putting on my shoes is a pain in the neck.
穿鞋子好麻烦
How can a young kid like you say things like that?
年纪轻轻说的什么话？
Nothing seems to matter anymore.
好像什么都不重要啦
Have you fallen in love?
谈恋爱了吗？
I bet I know.
就是这样
Before you were just fine by yourself.
以前觉得一个人也挺好的
But now you can't stand being alone.
现在却无法忍受寂寞
You buy a bunch of magazines and CDs to kill time when you're alone at night,
买一堆杂志和CD 为了晚上一个人时打发时间
but you're still really lonely.
但还是觉得很孤单
Yes.
没错
That is love.
这就是恋爱啦
You're amazing, Mr. Hirayama.
不愧是大叔
I'm an active pupil of love.
我也是个恋爱信徒啊
You mean you're still in love?
你也恋爱了吗？
In my case, I'm in love with my work.
对我来说 我爱的是我的工作
Oh, your work.
你的工作啊
You sure you want to sit here moping?
你确定要坐在这里自怨自艾吗？
Your rival could be thinking, "I'll tell her today how I feel!"
你的情敌可能正在想 “今天一定要跟她告白”
He's put his pants on.
他穿上裤子啦
He's just put on his right shoe!
他刚穿上右脚的鞋子
Ouch!
好痛！
See you!
我走啦
Bye.
再见
Yes, he's in love.
他真的恋爱了啊
What?
什么？
No way!
怎么会？
-Well-- -I thought of what we should do next.
-那个… -我想好接下来要做什么啦
Where did he go?
那家伙在哪？
Yip.
嗯
Come over here.
过来啊
What's your problem?
你有什么毛病？
Are you a shy fox or something?
你是害羞的狐狸吗？
You know what I realized?
我发现一件事
What you obviously lack is a flirtatious attitude.
你最欠缺的 就是跟别人打情骂俏的能力
A flirtatious attitude?
打情骂俏的能力？
Yes. You're not frisky.
没错 你不够活泼
So why don't you have a romance?
所以你要去谈恋爱呀
A romance?
谈恋爱？
Romance is great!
谈恋爱是很美好的
I heard it's great for your complexion.
听说皮肤会变得很光滑
Her complexion is plenty fine already! Are you blind, Shuji?
她的皮肤已经够光滑啦 修二 你瞎了吗？
Oh, would you shut up?
你能闭嘴吗？
Shut up.
别吵
Well…
那个…
Yes?
什么？
A love letter? For you?
情书？给你的？
No way! Really?
怎么会？真的吗？
It's from Shittaka!
是植木诚写的
What? No way!
什么？怎么会？
How come? Ouch!
为什么？好痛！
She loves me.
喜欢
She loves me not.
不喜欢
-You think he's a good choice? -Yes.
-你觉得他是好对象吗？ -是啊
She loves me not.
不喜欢
You think he's a good choice?
你觉得他是好对象？
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
You almost blew it.
差点就被你搞砸啦
What?
什么？
I…
我…
don't think I can do it.
我想我办不到
-It'll be just fine! Leave it to us. -No, it won't work.
-没事的 交给我们 -不 行不通的
Being in high school is the time for love! Right?
高中生就该谈恋爱 对吗？
That's it!
就是这个
A cheerful and pure romance between a man and a woman!
一段开心又单纯的恋爱
Let's do this!
就这么办
I'm a little… just a little…
只有一点点啦
attracted to her.
我觉得她不错
Me too.
我也是
To be honest, I think Kotani is kind of pretty too.
老实说 我也觉得小谷挺漂亮的
-You're kidding! You think so too? -Yes.
-真的假的？你也这么觉得？ -对啊
-You do? -And she'll just keep gaining popularity.
-是吗？ -她的人气只会越来越高
So you need to get her now.
所以你现在就必须把她追到手
That's right! That's exactly what I was thinking too!
对呀 我也是这么想的
You need to strike now because she'll be popular in no time.
要趁早出击啊 她马上就会变得很抢手啦
Say, why don't we go on a double date?
对啦 要不要来个四人约会？
A double date?
-四人约会？ -四人约会
-A double date? -Yes.
-对啊
I thought we could bring bento lunches too.
我想说可以做便当带去吃
Really.
好
But are you sure you will?
但你是认真的吗？
Don't be silly. Of course I'm sure.
你在说什么？我当然是认真的啊
Every time you promise to do something with me, you cancel at the last minute.
因为每次你答应我的事 都会在最后一刻取消
There! I got it!
有啦 挑出来啦
-Look. -Oh, you did it!
-你看 -真的呀
Wow! You're good at this kind of thing.
你真的很擅长这种事
That's why I want you to depend on me.
所以我才说交给我呀
-Okay. -Good.
-是啊 -很好
A date?
约会？
It's not one of those big deals though.
这也没什么大不了的
I'll be there too. It'll be fine. Okay?
我也会去 不会有事的 好吗？
But I've never gone on a date.
但我从来没有约会过
Then it's about time.
那应该是时候啦
I mean, do you plan on spending your whole life alone
你打算这辈子都一个人
without ever dating anyone?
不跟任何人约会吗？
Hey! Wait!
喂 等等
Ouch!
好痛
Get closer.
靠近一点
Come on, get closer.
快点靠近一点啊
Hurry.
动作快
What?
什么？
No! Don't run!
不行 别逃跑
Don't run!
别逃跑啊
No…
不行啊
She ran away.
她逃跑啦
-Shuji! -What?
-修二 -什么？
-I knew it! She hates me! -What's wrong?
-我就知道她讨厌我 -怎么啦？
-She ran off! -Really?
-她逃跑啦 -真的吗？
You've got it all wrong! That's her way of saying she likes you.
你误会啦 那就是她表达喜欢你的方式啊
-But… -"Her way of saying she likes you"?
-但是… -“她表达喜欢你的方式”？
Never mind.
没事
-She rejected you? -What's going on?
-她拒绝你？ -怎么回事？
Who? Who loves who?
谁啊？谁喜欢谁？
-You mean you, Shittaka? -Who? Who do you like?
-你是说植木诚吗？ -谁？你喜欢谁？
Kotani!
是小谷
Kotani just rejected you, right?
你刚被小谷拒绝啦？
I saw it.
我看到啦
No way! You like Kotani, Shittaka?
真的吗？你喜欢小谷吗？
-Quit shouting! -And she rejected you?
-别大声嚷嚷 -她拒绝你啦？
She didn't reject him. They're just getting started.
她没有拒绝他 才刚开始而已
You mean, she'll reject me later?
你是说她之后还会拒绝我吗？
No! Not that!
我不是那个意思
What's so great about Kotani?
小谷有什么好啊？
When someone falls in love, that's…
喜欢上一个人…
something beautiful, right?
是很美好的事 对吗？
-Yes.
-对啊 -就是说啊
-That's right. -It's beautiful.
-没错 -很美好
Dates, you see, they're a really casual thing. Okay?
这只是很随性的约会 好吗？
I mean, Shittaka says he really likes you.
植木诚说他真的很喜欢你
-"I don't like him." -You'll ignore his feelings for you?
-“我不喜欢他” -你要无视他的心意吗？
"Of course, I'll ignore them!"
“当然 我会无视的”
-You'll go. Right? Let's go. -"I'm not going. I'm not going!"
-你会去 对吗？ -“我不去”
"I'm not going. I'm not!"
“我不去 我不要”
Yes! Let's do our best, Nobuta!
太好啦 我们一起加油 野猪
-No! -What?
-讨厌 -什么？
That's lewd!
色狼
-What is? -No!
-不要
You won't go, right?
你不会去？
There's no way she'll go.
她怎么可能会去？
When you hear this laugh, it means there will be misfortune.
听到这个笑声 代表会有厄运降临
This date won't go well.
这场约会肯定不会顺利
What the heck is that?
那是什么声音？
-Isn't it coming from the sky? -Yes.
-是不是从天上传来的？ -是啊
Not this laugh again!
又是那个笑声
I guess something bad will happen again.
我猜又有坏事要发生啦
Wait! When you hear this laugh, bad things happen?
等等 听到这个笑声 就会有坏事发生吗？
-That's the rumor. -Really?
-那是谣言 -真的吗？
Last year, Class 2C's trouble with the police was
去年2年C班跟警方发生纠纷
right after we heard this laugh, right?
就是在我们听到笑声之后 对吗？
Oh, yeah. That was a huge problem.
没错 那造成了很大的问题啊
I pray that it doesn't involve my class!
希望跟我们班无关
Don't you think it sounds like Head Teacher Sada's laugh?
不觉得那听起来 很像佐田老师的笑声吗？
That's what I've always thought.
我一直都这么想的
Right?
对吗？
Hey!
喂
-Wait! -That's uncool!
-等等 -别闹啦
-Mr. Saotome! Wait! -Hey!
-早乙女老师 等等 -喂
Oh, I didn't know that.
“我都不知道
You sure are smart, Shittaka.
你果然很聪明 植木诚”
If you talk like that, you'll flatter him. That's what's important. Okay?
这样称赞他是很重要的 懂吗？
And no more running away.
还有不准再逃跑啦
If he tries to touch you,
如果他想碰你
then gently refuse him.
你就温柔地拒绝
Gently.
温柔地
I'll show you how to do that. Here goes.
我来示范给你看 看好啦
-If he goes like-- -Stop!
-如果他这样… -等一下
I'll handle it from there.
接下来换我示范
Sure, go ahead.
好啊 你来呀
Get over there.
去那里
Excuse me.
不好意思
If Shittaka tries to make a move on you…
如果植木诚想对你毛手毛脚…
"Make a move"?
毛手毛脚？
-How lewd! -What?
-色狼 -什么？
Why not say "put his arm around you"?
为什么不说“搭肩”就好？
Who cares what you call it?
你爱怎么形容都可以啦
Fine. If Shittaka tries to put his arm around you…
好 如果植木诚试图搭你的肩…
Put your arm around her.
去搭她的肩
Go on. Do it. Right.
去呀 开始 没错
What?
什么？
-I can't move! -What?
-我动不了啦 -什么？
-My arm won't move! -What's your problem?
-我的手臂动不了 -你有什么问题？
Enough! I'm taking over!
够啦 换人…
So if Shittaka comes at you like this--
所以 如果植木诚这样对你…
Wait! I have an idea!
等等 我有个好主意
Shuji, you and I, we'll do it.
修二 我们两个来示范
How come?
为什么？
That way, if she can see it for herself, it's easier for her to understand.
这样她才能亲眼看见也更容易理解
Oh, I guess you're right.
说得也是
So who is who?
那谁是谁？
You be Nobuta. I'll be Shittaka.
你来当野猪 我是植木诚
I'm Nobuta. Okay.
我是野猪 好的
I'll play you. Watch closely.
我扮演你 仔细看好啦
Okay.
好啦
I…
我…
-I love you! -Don't.
-我喜欢你 -不行
Don't do that.
别这样
-But… -Don't.
-但是… -不行
I love you so much, my heart is about to burst.
我喜欢你喜欢到心脏都快跳出来啦
What does that mean?
人家听不懂啦
I love you this much!
我有这么喜欢你
I like you too.
我也喜欢你
Oops!
糟糕
Wait!
等等
-It's not what you think! -Don't worry.
-不是你想的那样 -别担心
My lips are sealed.
我口风很紧的
Don't worry!
别担心
LEMON AND HONEY
（柠檬蜂蜜）
Since we're trying to get Kotani and Shittaka together,
既然我们要撮合小谷和植木诚
if you're there, Mariko,
如果真理子你在的话
Kotani's flaws…
小谷的缺点
They'll be more obvious.
就会更明显啦
Give me that.
给我
Then why don't I play a totally horrible girlfriend?
那我就来演一个糟糕透顶的女友
I'll make her look good. Leave it to me.
我会衬托她的 交给我
-Make her look good? -Yes.
-衬托她？ -是啊
You will?
你吗？
No way. You'll never be able to do that.
不可能 你绝对不可能做到
There.
拿去
Wow!
好厉害
Leave it to me.
交给我
Can you tell me the key to making a date a success?
那你可以告诉我 约会成功的关键吗？
The key?
关键？
At the end of it, if you say, "I had fun today," that's the key.
就是在最后说“今天很开心”
Oh, I get it.
我懂啦
It kind of means, "I want to do it again."
仿佛在说“我还想再跟你出来”
Right. But Kotani needs to say it from the heart.
没错 但小谷必须发自内心的说
Good point! That's right.
说得好 没错
It has to come from the heart! From the heart!
一定要发自内心 打从心底地说
That's really crucial.
这真的很重要
It has to come from the heart.
一定要发自内心
There.
好啦
Okay, they're ready.
好 都准备好啦
This is for Shittaka. This is Nobuta's.
这是植木诚的 这是野猪的
And Mariko will bring mine.
我的那份真理子会帮我带
Where's mine?
那我的？
-You're not part of this. -Here.
-跟你无关 -来
-Your tea. -Thank you so much!
-你们的茶 -不好意思
Thank you so much!
谢谢
There.
好啦
Then what am I supposed to do?
那我要做什么？
Nothing. Just stay here.
什么都不用做 待在这里就好
Watch TV or something.
看个电视之类的
You guys go on a date while I have to sit at home?
你们去约会 我却待在家里？
If you're there, that puts everything out of balance.
有你在 会把一切搞得乱七八糟
Don't you dare come.
你千万别来啊
Here.
给你
-There's something on your face. -I put it there.
-你脸上有东西 -是我贴的
-We're going! Thanks. -See you later.
-我们要出发啦 谢谢 -慢走
-Goodbye.
-出发啦 -再见
Yip.
嗯
-What are you doing here? -I don't know.
你在这里做什么？
Was the baby left behind?
小孩子被留下来了吗？
I won't stand for this!
我这次不会饶过你
Okay.
那么…
Try saying, "I had fun today."
你说说看“今天很开心”
"I had fun today."
“今天很开心”
That's not quite right. Try being more energetic.
感觉不太对 要更有活力一点
Like…
像是…
"I had fun today!"
“今天很开心”
Okay?
这样的感觉
Good enough.
算啦
How about we practice holding hands?
我们来练习牵手？
What? Ouch!
什么？好痛
Hi, Kotani!
喂 小谷
She's nervous.
她很紧张
Morning.
早安
Let's have a good time today.
今天请多多指教
I had…
今天…
fun today.
很开心
Let's have a day like that.
让我们拥有那样的一天
Let's have a fun day.
一起开心地度过今天
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
那么出发啦 走呀
Come on. Let's go.
来 快跟上
Hurry up.
快点
Yip.
嗯
Hurry up, you guys.
你们快一点啦
Kotani, isn't this cute?
小谷 这是不是很可爱？
Oh, look at this!
你看这个
-And this. -This?
还有这个
Yes.
-这个吗？ -对啊
-What do you want to do next? -Is there anything you want, Shuji?
-接下来想做什么？ -修二 你有想去的地方吗？
Which of these do you think is best?
你觉得哪个比较好？
How about this one?
这个？
We don't need that many.
我们不需要那么多
-Get a matching set. -A matching set.
-买一对的 -一对的
-I want to ride the Ferris wheel. -The Ferris wheel?
-我想去坐摩天轮 -摩天轮？
That sounds fun!
听起来很好玩
Sir,
先生
how would you like a magnificent insect encyclopedia?
想不想看一本豪华的昆虫百科全书？
How about it?
怎么样？
A hundred million yen?
一亿日元？
-Okay, let's have lunch. -Let's have lunch.
-好 来吃午餐啦 -我们来吃午餐呀
Bento time.
吃便当的时间到啦
This is so darn cute!
这也太可爱啦
Here goes!
我开动啦
-No way! -Looks good, doesn't it?
-怎么会？ -是不是看起来很好吃？
What? Oh, yeah. Really good.
什么？没错 真的很棒
Today, she made it to look like charcoal.
今天她弄得像木炭一样
You always eat stuff like this?
你平常都吃这些东西吗？
That's right. It's extra special.
是啊 今天比较丰盛
-Extra special? -It's usually just this.
-这样算丰盛？ -平常就只有这样
-Shuji. -Yes?
-修二 -什么？
Here.
来
Not that. It has to be the stuff from the store.
不是这种茶 我只喝店里卖的
What?
什么？
Go buy some.
去买啦
Oh, sure.
没问题
And it better be hot.
最好是热的
Oh, yeah. You're right.
对 我知道
You always want it hot. Sorry. I forgot. Sorry.
你总是喝热的 抱歉 我忘啦
-I'll go buy some. -Okay.
-我去买 -好
Shuji. Is Uehara always like that?
修二 上原一直都是这样吗？
Oh, yeah.
是啊
Oh, I see.
这样啊
I'll go buy that tea, but you go ahead and eat.
我去买茶 你们先吃
Okay.
好
-This is great! -I'll go buy some.
-真好吃 -我去买
This is really good.
这真的很好吃
What should I have next?
接下来要吃什么？
-Can I have this? -Wait!
-这个可以给我吗？ -等等
There's only one of those!
那只有一个
Delicious!
好吃
What the heck are you doing?
你在做什么？
What?
做什么？
What a coincidence!
这么巧啊？
-I told you not to come! -You know, we may be the best couple ever!
-我叫你不要来 -我们可能是史上最速配的情侣
Don't you dare interfere.
你休息插手
-Okay?
-好吗？
Don't you dare interfere!
你不准插手
-Look how close they are together! -Get back here!
-你看他们离得这么近 -给我回来
The chance they'll be a couple is now 99.99 percent!
成为情侣的几率是99.99%
All right!
太好啦
This won't succeed.
不会成功的
-What? -This won't succeed.
-什么？ -才不会成功
Don't you dare interfere, man!
你不准插手
Don't interfere!
别乱来
I'm back!
我回来啦
We've got other plans.
我们还要去别的地方
We're going shopping in Ginza.
我们要去银座买东西
Bye.
再见
-Bye. -See you.
-再见
Shittaka. You can do it!
植木诚 加油
Let's go.
走啦
-Shuji, -Yes?
-修二 -什么？
you're acting like Kotani's father.
你就像小谷的爸爸一样
What? Her father?
什么？她父亲？
-That's right. -That's a shock.
-没错 -我才不像
-You're like her father. -I am not.
-你就像她爸爸 -不像啦
Say, are you thirsty?
你渴不渴？
I'll get you something. Hold on.
我去帮你买喝的 等一下
Nobuta power charge!
野猪能量 注入
What a goofball.
真是个傻瓜
You're in the middle of a date.
你明明就在约会啊
-Thanks. -Sure.
-谢谢 -不客气
-You know, sorry about today. -It's okay.
-今天的事很抱歉 -没关系
I wonder if it'll go well for those two.
不知道他们相处的怎么样
It'll be just fine. You did a great job playing the awful girlfriend.
会很顺利 你演坏女友演得很好
I had fun today.
我今天很开心
Okay…
好的
I guess my heart wasn't in it.
我好像没有发自内心地说
They're really cute.
真的好可爱
Here goes.
要拍啦
Say cheese.
笑一个
Akira's in shock!
阿彰心碎
The ending of the movie Carrie,
史蒂芬金显然不喜欢
Stephen King apparently didn't like it.
《魔女嘉莉》的结局
But that's the movie that made him popular.
但他是因为那部电影出名
De Palma's movie is really scary.
狄帕马的电影真的很恐怖
The end will scare you for sure.
结局都很吓人
It suddenly shocks you!
会突然吓到你的那种
Are…
你…
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
What will we do?
我们该怎么办？
"What will we do?"
“我们该怎么办？”
-Oh, no. -Mister, are you okay?
-糟啦 -大叔 你有事吗？
Anyway, call an ambulance.
快叫救护车
An ambulance?
救护车？
I'll call it.
我来打电话
Thank you.
谢谢
Hello?
喂？
-Mister, are you okay? -I'm at the aquarium.
-大叔 你有事吗？ -我现在人在水族馆
A man.
一个男人
-We're calling an ambulance now. -His age? He's an old man.
-我们叫救护车啦 -年纪？他是个老人
Get my bag.
帮我拿包包
Gross!
好恶心
Bang!
砰
No! No, that's not what I mean!
不是 我不是那个意思
That's the hand you touched him with!
你用那双手碰他
No…
不
That's not what I mean.
我不是那个意思
I meant…
我是说
I'll get a staff member.
我去找工作人员
You're not gross at all.
你一点都不恶心
Look at this.
你看
What a gentle hand this is.
这双手好温柔
Isn't that right, mister?
对吗 大叔？
You did so much for me.
你们为我做了那么多事
I'm sorry.
对不起
You mean about the date?
你是说约会的事吗？
For my sake,
为了我
you all did so much. Even Uehara.
你们做了很多努力 连上原也是
It's not your fault, you know, Nobuta.
这不是你的错 野猪
But if I had done a better job…
但如果我表现得更好
I wanted to live up to
我不想…
your expectations.
辜负你们的期望
I wanted it to go well…
我希望一切顺利
and then
然后…
I could tell all of you "thank you."
可以跟你们说声“谢谢”
There you are.
你们在这里啊
Apparently, the old man had a little too much to drink.
那位大叔喝多啦
He's talking normally now. He's fine.
他现在能正常说话啦 他没事
Bye.
我先走啦
Thank goodness.
太好啦
HOSPITAL
（医院）
The sky sure is beautiful.
天空真漂亮
Yes.
是啊
It's the kind of sky that makes you want to play catch.
这种天空会让人很想玩传接球
I never have though.
我从来没有那样玩过
These two
这两个人
are always throwing the ball to me.
总是会把球丢给我
But all I can do is just catch it.
但我能做的就只有接住球
That's why I want to toss it back to them someday.
所以我希望有一天能把球丢回给他们
If I could throw it
我希望自己可以回传
so it fell right into their gloves,
将球丢进他们的手套
that sure would feel nice.
那种感觉一定很棒
I'm home!
我回来啦
Is she alive?
她还活着吗？
She collapsed after returning from her trip.
她出差回来后就开始昏睡
So leave her be and let her sleep.
所以别管她啦 让她睡
-I bought the okra. -Welcome back.
-我买秋葵回来啦 -你回来啦
Not sure why, but she shouted "okra" in her sleep. Right?
不确定是为什么 但她在睡梦中喊了“秋葵” 对吗？
Right.
对
Broccoli?
西兰花？
Koji.
浩二
Broccoli.
西兰花
-Yes. -What?
-拿去 -什么？
Broccoli too?
还要买西兰花？
So what about the shabu-shabu?
那涮锅的肉？
It's postponed until your mother wakes up.
等你妈醒来再开始涮肉
What?
什么？
-I was looking forward to that meat. -Meat!
-我很期待那些肉 -肉
Meat!
肉
You're not gross at all.
你一点都不恶心
My hand!
我的手
I…
我…
That was really bold!
太大胆啦
Oh, dear! I'm so ashamed!
天啊 真害羞
Nobuta!
野猪
Nobuta! Ouch!
野猪 好痛
Nobuta! I don't think I can look at her face now!
野猪 我现在没脸见她啦
I'm so ashamed! Oh, dear! What'll I do?
太害羞啦 天啊 怎么办？
Oh, no! I can't see!
不 我看不到
I can't see a thing!
我什么都看不到
A young man, burning with desire alone.
年轻人欲火焚身啊
Oh, dear!
天啊
Nobuta!
野猪
"Nobuko Kotani's shocking relationship with men."
“小谷信子令人震惊的恋情”
-"Disgusting woman, Nobuko Kotani." -What is this?
-“恶心的女人 小谷信子” -这是什么？
"Her next prey is Ueki from class 2B."
“下个猎物是2年B班的植木诚”
-What a slut! -No way!
-真是个荡妇 -怎么会？
NOBUKO KOTANI'S SHOCKING RELATIONSHIP WITH MEN.
（小谷信子令人震惊的恋情）
What? What's up? This place sure is colorful.
什么？怎么啦？这里真是五彩缤纷
What?
什么？
It's my class again.
又是我的班级
I hate this kind of thing.
我最讨厌这种事啦
Hey.
喂
You know,
你知道
even after these flyers were posted, Shittaka says he still wants to date you.
就算传单贴成这样 植木诚说他还是想跟你交往
If you actually do date,
如果你们真的交往的话
everybody will forget these rumors.
大家就会忘记这些谣言
So
所以
why don't you make up with him?
你就跟他和好？
But Shittaka called Nobuta gross.
但是植木诚说野猪恶心
He regrets what he said.
他很后悔自己说了那些话
He's sorry about it.
他觉得很抱歉
So you see, he wants you to forgive him.
所以他希望你原谅他
You're still upset?
你还在生气吗？
I just think dating someone who I don't like
我只是觉得跟不喜欢的人交往
is wrong.
是不对的
What are you talking about? Everyone does it.
你在说什么？大家都是这样啊
You need experience in order to learn how to get along with people.
你需要积累经验 才能知道怎么跟人相处
I mean, you want to become popular, right?
你想受欢迎 对吗？
Aren't you doing all these things to become popular?
你做这些不都是希望受欢迎吗？
Aren't you?
不是吗？
No.
不是
"No"?
“不是”？
But isn't that why we're doing all this work?
但那不就是我们这么努力的原因吗？
Isn't it?
对吗？
You mean,
你是说
you don't want to become popular?
你不想变得受欢迎吗？
What? Are you kidding?
什么？你在开玩笑吗？
Now I feel like a total idiot.
现在我觉得自己像个白痴
This doesn't make any sense.
这说不通啊
These flyers are everywhere, you know?
校园里都是这些传单 你知道吗？
Before long, nobody will talk to you!
很快就不会有人跟你说话啦
Understand?
你明白吗？
You believe those flyers?
你相信那些传单的内容？
This isn't about whether I believe them or not!
这不是我相不相信的问题
Of course, I don't believe them!
我当然不相信
But these things were plastered all over!
但是这些东西贴满了全校
It's only a matter of time before everyone believes them!
大家迟早会相信的
Understand?
你明白吗？
"With all these flyers around, Nobuta will be worthless soon,
“到处都是传单 野猪很快就没价值啦
so let's sell her cheap now!"
所以趁现在便宜卖”
That's what it sounds like you're saying.
你听起来就是这个意思
Nobuta is Nobuta.
野猪就是野猪
Even with these flyers out there,
就算外面有这些传单
Nobuta is the same Nobuta we both know.
野猪还是我们认识的野猪
She's the same person she's always been.
她还是原来的她
-These flyers are frightening. -Yes.
-这些传单真可怕 -是啊
-They were in the girls' restroom. -The boys' too.
-女厕都贴满啦 -男厕也是
The gym too.
体育馆也有
-They're all over school. -Yes.
-全校都贴满啦 -对啊
Kotani is pretty bad, but I heard Mariko Uehara is really nasty too.
虽然小谷很差劲 但听说上原真理子也很糟糕
I heard she's a terrible cook.
听说她厨艺很差
Really? I guess she's all talk.
真的吗？原来她只会说大话
Did you hear about Uehara?
你听说上原的事了吗？
No! What about her?
没有 她怎么啦？
I heard she doesn't make her bento lunches herself.
我听说她的便当都不是自己做的
-Seriously? What a fraud! -Yes!
-真的吗？真是个大骗子 -对啊
Excuse me for a second.
失陪一下
What's wrong, Shuji?
修二 怎么啦？
Well…
那个…
Because of yesterday's date,
因为昨天的约会
bad rumors about you are spreading now too.
现在连你都有负面的传闻啦
Well…
这样啊
That's all right.
没关系
But they're not true.
但那些都不是事实
You know the truth, Shuji. That's enough for me.
修二 你知道真相就够啦
But…
但是…
I told you. I don't mind.
我说过啦 我不介意的
As long as someone knows the truth, that's enough for me.
只要有人知道真相 我就心满意足啦
Since you know the truth, that's good enough.
只要你知道真相就好
Sorry, but I've got to go back to practice.
抱歉 我得回去练习啦
-Okay. -Bye.
-好 -再见
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
I caught that bird that's been doing that crazy laughing.
我抓到那只一直狂笑的鸟啦
It's a myna bird.
是八哥啊
That's right. A myna bird.
没错 是八哥
It must have escaped from its owner.
应该是从主人那里逃出来的
Everyone says it sounds like me.
大家都说它的声音很像我
You troublemaker!
你这个麻烦鬼
It was a bird?
原来是鸟啊
What?
你说什么？
Wait a minute here.
等一下
Even the calm and cool Shuji Kiritani
就连沉稳淡定的桐谷修二
was deceived by that rumor?
也被那个传闻给骗啦？
Oh, say…
对啦
Are you letting this kind of thing deceive you too?
你被这种东西给骗啦？
Kiritani, do not be afraid.
桐谷 不要害怕
This is nothing but garbage.
这只是垃圾
It's the kind of garbage you find anywhere.
是随处可见的垃圾
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Oh, it's you.
是你啊
Mom went off for work again.
你妈又去工作啦
But what are you doing, Dad?
但你在做什么 爸？
The plane she's on will be passing by pretty soon.
她搭的那班飞机很快就会经过
You're hardly ever together, so what was the point of getting married?
你们相处的时间那么少 到底结婚有什么意义？
Don't be stupid. We got married because we are hardly ever together.
别傻啦 我们结婚就是因为 我们很少见面
Now that we're married, I can see her at least a few times a year.
结婚后 一年至少能见她几次
Seriously?
真的吗？
You bet. I'm totally serious.
当然 我是认真的
Just knowing that there's someone somewhere in this world
只要知道这个世界上有某个人
who knows everything cool about me,
知道我所有很酷的事
and everything lame and pathetic about me is good enough.
还有所有丢脸 可悲的事 那样就足够啦
That's all I need.
那样我就心满意足啦
Hey.
喂
Is that it?
是那一架吗？
That's it!
就是它
Nobutan!
小野猪
"Nobutan"?
“小野猪”？
Yes. That's what I used to call her.
对 我以前都是这么叫她的
Nobutan!
小野猪
I just think dating someone who I don't like is wrong.
我只是觉得 跟不喜欢的人交往是不对的
Shuji.
修二
What's with you?
怎么啦？
What do you want?
你想干什么？
Come with me.
跟我来
What? Why?
什么？为什么？
Yip.
嗯
What's this about?
你到底想干吗？
We're going to tail Nobuta.
我们去跟踪野猪
How come?
为什么？
Come on.
快跟上
Here, she practices smiling with Tarokichi, the dog.
她会在这里和狗狗太郎吉练习微笑
And here,
然后到这里
she always says a prayer.
她总是会祈祷
She gazes at the vegetables but never buys any.
她盯着那些蔬菜看 却从来不买
They…
这些花…
They're very pretty.
很漂亮
You're very pretty too.
你也很漂亮
And she talks with the florist.
她会和花店的阿姨聊天
Us two…
我们两个…
we don't know anything about Nobuta.
对野猪一无所知
In fact, we never even tried to learn more about her.
事实上 我们从未试着多了解她
Do you know what her wish is?
你知道她的愿望是什么吗？
To become popular someday
希望有一天能变得受欢迎
and then tell you, "Thank you!"
然后跟你说“谢谢”
Nobuta!
野猪
Shuji has something to say to you!
修二有话要跟你说
You know…
你知道吗？
I want to make you popular.
我希望让你变得受欢迎
And then, I want to see you laugh at silly things…
然后我希望你像个普通女孩一样
until you double over and cry
因为愚蠢的事
like any ordinary girl would.
笑到流眼泪
Like I was told, the flyers turned into just garbage.
就像我听到的那样 传单全都变成垃圾啦
And the date caused something unexpected.
那场约会有了意料之外的结果
Kotani.
小谷
The man you helped was my grandpa.
你救的人是我爷爷
Oh, is that right?
是吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
My grandpa was really happy.
我爷爷超开心的
Come see him sometime. It'll make him happy for sure.
有空来看看他 这样他一定会很开心的
Okay?
好吗？
Okay.
好
Nobuta made a friend.
野猪交到朋友啦
Nobuta…
野猪
Let's go.
走吧
There's something I can't help thinking right now.
我一直在想一件事
I don't want to lose to
我真的不想
anyone who isn't honestly pleased when other people find joy.
输给那些见不得别人好的人
You don't know it?
你不知道吗？
Then I'll take you there sometime.
之后我再带你去
Do you like monjayaki, Kotani?
小谷 你喜欢文字烧吗？
I definitely don't want them to get the best of me.
我绝对不能被那些人影响
Yes, I do.
是 我喜欢
We'll get rich off of Nobuta?
我们能靠野猪致富？
We'll be rolling in cash!
我们会赚大钱的
You young people obsessed with money!
你们年轻人就是见钱眼开
Shall be punished!
天罚！
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey
字幕翻译：张欣怡